JIBRIL ABDURRASHID

15 Hopkins Ave, Apt 41 Jersey City, NJ 07306

Email: jabdurrashid@gmail.com Phone: (917) 496-7839

Senior lead with significant and progressive experience focused on Middleware infrastructure within the Financial Services industry. Hands on subject matter expert uniquely experienced in various disciplines from service operations in a data center to collaborating with application architects around the world in service design. Proven leader, capable of leading initiatives that deliver solutions to improve service.

IT SERVICES

Amazon Web Service: Route53, ELB, VPC, EC2, S3, EBS, AWS CLI

Web Servers: Apache 2.x, NginX, IBM IHS 7, SUN One 6.x, iPlanet 4.x, IIS 7.0/6.0/5.0/4.0

Application Servers: Oracle WebLogic Server & Portal 12c/11g/10.x, Tomcat

<u>Security Devices</u>: IBM WebSphere DataPower Integration Appliance XI50, Barracuda Web Application Firewall, Juniper Secure Access (SA), Juniper Data Center Acceleration (DX), Netcontinuum Application Security Gateway

Applications: Serena Business Manager, Ansible, Jenkins, ServiceNow, Borland StarTeam, Github, Confluence, JIRA, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint, Bash, HP Service Manager, BMC Remedy IT Service Management (ITSM), Netegrity SiteMinder 6.0, SharePoint, Visio, Magic, SiteScope, NetBackup DataCenter 3.4, Interwoven Teamsite 5.x, ProjectWeb, MS Project

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

AWS CERTIFIED SYSOPS ADMINISTRATOR - ASSOCIATE (2017)

AWS CERTIFIED DEVELOPER - ASSOCIATE (2017)

ITIL INTERMEDIATE: SERVICE OPERATION (2015)

ITIL INTERMEDIATE: SERVICE TRANSITION (2015)

ITIL INTERMEDIATE: CONTINUAL SERVICE IMPROVEMENT (2014)

PRINCE2 PROJECT MANAGEMENT PRACTITIONER (2006)

SUN CERTIFIED SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR FOR SOLARIS 8 (2002)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TIAA 5/2015 – 11/2016

Senior Engineer, Enterprise Infrastructure Services - Middleware

Middleware Lead

- Utilize ITIL Service Operations, Service Transition, and Continual Service Improvement exposure to lead global vendor managed services second level 24/7 team to ensure that 197 internal & external facing products are available on traditional and Amazon Web Service cloud infrastructure.
- Key member of improvement projects to upgrade all WebLogic data sources to Oracle Active GridLink configurations to improve High Availability and a cost savings project to migrate applications to Amazon Web Services for scalability and elasticity.
- Collaborate with Release Management on the evaluation and implementation of scheduled monthly enterprise releases to ensure that tasks have been vetted, assigned, and if possible automated.
- Coordinate the staging of production enhancements with Application Development, Software Configuration Management, and DevOps.
- Represent middleware in weekly planning sessions to review servers and applications that will be affected by Vulnerability patching, SAN migrations, and High Availability implementations.

J.P. Morgan

VP, Service Delivery

10/2013-5/2015

Middleware TechOps Lead for Platform as a Service

 Perform monthly Service Reviews with senior management, which detail customer footprints, Capacity, Risk Control Self Assessment scorecard, Change Management, Incident volumes, and Business Process Index.

- Implemented procedures to identify data quality issues that were significantly impacting our key Business Process Index metric and to influence Service Operations leaders to implement service improvements to ensure our service exceeds the 99.90% expected uptime.
- Represent PaaS in weekly meetings with various external Risk, Vulnerability, Resiliency, and Service Operations teams to analyze service metrics and progress on initiatives.
- Drive the collaboration with Risk team on Risk Control Self Assessments, Audit Action plans, and Vulnerability management to ensure that my team provides accurate substantiation and resolves any potential security violations.
- Responsible for Configuration Management of all PaaS Managed Services owned components by ensuring accurate ownership is detailed in the configuration management database (CMDB) and other inventory tools.

J.P. Morgan

VP, CIB Middleware Niche Technology

12/2011-10/2013

Web Middleware Team Lead for Corporate & Investment Bank.

- Managed a small team of Middleware Subject Matter Experts in a DevOps environment to ensure that our JPM Access Portal application is available to approximately 50,000 users across the globe.
- Responsible for Problem Ownership and Root Cause analysis on all Web Middleware infrastructure incidents escalated to my team via HP Service Manager. Collaborate with Vendors, Service Delivery, System Administration, Database Administration, and other infrastructure teams to find resolutions to complex application issues.
- Responsible for reviewing, approving, and resource allocation for all planned Middleware implementations via a BMC Remedy IT Service Management (ITSM) corporate wide change management approval process.

J.P. Morgan

AVP, Treasury Services

1/2007-12/2011

- Web Middleware Project Engineer
- Provide Web Middleware Subject Matter Expertise to Application Development Architects to build enterprise applications that are critical to the success of the firm on a global scale. The collaboration includes project implementation; capacity planning, performance tuning, vendor engagement, and root cause analysis.
- Utilized proven PRINCE2 Practitioner project management techniques to lead multiple middleware project types that range from new enterprise technologies to quarterly application enhancements.
- Write application specific technical documentation for off-shore Follow The Sun support personnel, which details all web middleware infrastructure components of the product and proven trouble shooting techniques.
- Ensure Internet facing enterprise applications are secured behind Barracuda Web Application Firewalls that protect against malicious attacks, data theft, web site cloaking, and other vulnerabilities that may pose reputational risk to the firm.

Credit Suisse 10/2003-11/2006

Technical Specialist, Global Web Services

Project Lead, designed, configured, and managed business critical web application infrastructure for Equities, Fixed Income, and Asset Management divisions within Credit Suisse.

- Configured J2EE & .NET applications to utilize Sun One or IIS 6 web servers, WebLogic 8.1 application servers, Cisco GSS & CSS load balancing, and Siteminder identity management.
- Documented web product infrastructure, detailing application components with graphical load balancing configurations, business continuity plan, content management, and proven troubleshooting techniques. This documentation was the primary tool used by second level support to troubleshoot the application.
- Migrated 20 Internet & intranet web applications configured on end-of-service-life IIS 4 web servers to IIS 6 web servers. Successfully coordinated the migrations and application checkouts with stakeholders for DEV, UAT, DR, and PROD instances.
- Performed regularly scheduled Service Transitions utilizing Interwoven's Teamsite 5.x and Opendeploy content management tools to submit and publish new editions to production.

Thomson Reuters 10/2000-10/2003

Systems Operator, Business Systems Hosting

Provide Incident Management for web applications, server hardware, operating systems, network components, and data management for business units within Thomson Reuters in order to minimize any downtime for our clients.

- Responsible for the administration and support of over 60 production websites hosted on Solaris,
 Windows 2000, and Redhat servers in the Global Network Operations Center.
- Applied skills achieved from SUN Solaris 8 Certification to provide second level UNIX administration and support to Production, Quality Assurance, and Development environments, which resulted in a 20% decrease in escalated issues to the UNIX administration team.
- Used the Korn Shell to write a customized shell script to consolidate departmental-wide monitoring software.
- Ensured data resiliency through automated system backups configured in VERITAS NetBackup and achieved a successful completion rate of 99%. Engaged off-site document management vendor to schedule storage and data recovery.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

B.Sc., Computer Information Systems (Baruch College)

A.SC, COMPUTER SCIENCE (MEDGER EVERS COLLEGE)

LEAN SIX SIGMA - DRIVE CONTINUOUS IMPROVEMENT (TIAA)

ITIL Intermediate: Service Operation (Mountainview ITSM)

ITIL Intermediate: Service Transition (LearningTree)

ITIL Intermediate: Continual Service Improvement (LearningTree)

BEA WebLogic Server 9/10: Monitoring and Performance Tuning (BEA)

BEA WebLogic Server 9/10: Advanced System Administration (BEA)

PRINCE2 Foundation & Practitioner (LearningTree)

Basic Project Management (NEW YORK UNIVERSITY)

BEA Weblogic Server 8.1: Tailored Troubleshooting Methodologies (BEA)